Chapter 1
Mr. Jones of the Manor Farm had locked the hen houses for the night, but was
too drunk to remember to shut the pop holes.
With the ring of light from his lantern dancing from side to side, he lurched
across the yard, kicked off his boots at the back door, drew himself a last glass
of beer from the barrel in the scullery, and made his way up to bed, where Mrs.
Jones was already snoring.
As soon as the light in the bedroom went out, there was a stirring and a
fluttering all through the farm buildings.
Word had gone round during the day that Old Major, the prize middle white boar,
had had a strange dream on the previous night and wished to communicate it to the other animals.
It had been agreed that they should all meet in the big barn as soon as Mr.
Jones was safely out of the way.
Old Major, so he was always called, though the name under which he had been
exhibited was Willingdon Beauty, was so highly regarded on the farm that
everyone was quite ready to lose an hour's sleep in order to hear what he had to say.
At one end of the big barn, on a sort of raised platform, Major was already
ensconced on his bed of straw under a lantern which hung from a beam.
He was 12 years old and had lately grown rather stout, but he was still a
majestic looking pig with a wise and benevolent appearance, in spite of the
fact that his tushes had never been cut.
Before long, the other animals began to arrive and make themselves comfortable
after their different fashions.
First came the three dogs, Bluebell, Jessie, and Pincher.
And then the pigs, who settled down in the straw immediately in front of the platform.
The hens perched themselves on the window sills, the pigeons fluttered up to the rafters,
the sheep and cows lay down behind the pigs and began to chew the cud.
The two cart horses, Boxer and Clover, came in together, walking very slowly and setting down
their vast hairy hooves with great care, lest there should be some small animal
concealed in the straw.
Clover was a stout, motherly mare approaching middle life who had never
quite got her figure back after her fourth foal.
Boxer was an enormous beast, nearly 18 hands high, and as strong as any two
ordinary horses put together.
A white stripe down his nose gave him a somewhat stupid appearance,
and in fact, he was not of first-rate intelligence, but he was universally respected for his
steadiness of character and tremendous powers of work.
After the horses came Muriel, the white goat, and Benjamin, the donkey.
Benjamin was the oldest animal on the farm and the worst-tempered.
He seldom talked, and when he did, it was usually to make some cynical remark.
For instance, he would say that God had given him a tail to keep the flies off,
but that he would sooner have had no tail and no flies.
Alone among the animals on the farm, he never laughed.
If asked why, he would say that he saw nothing to laugh at.
Nevertheless, without openly admitting it, he was devoted to Boxer.
The two of them usually spent their Sundays together in the small paddock
beyond the orchard, grazing side by side and never speaking.
The two horses had just lain down when a brood of ducklings, which had lost their
mother, filed into the barn, cheeping feebly and wandering from side to side
to find some place where they would not be trodden on.
Clover made a sort of wall round them with her great foreleg and the ducklings
nestled down inside it and promptly fell asleep.
At the last moment, Mollie, the foolish, pretty white mare who drew Mr. Jones's
trap, came mincing daintily in, chewing at a lump of sugar.
She took a place near the front and began flirting her white mane, hoping to
draw attention to the red ribbons it was plaited with.
Last of all came the cat, who looked round, as usual, for the warmest place
and finally squeezed herself in between Boxer and Clover.
There she purred contentedly throughout Major's speech without listening to a
word of what he was saying.
All the animals were now present except Moses, the tame raven, who slept on a
perch behind the back door.
When Major saw that they had all made themselves comfortable and were waiting attentively,
he cleared his throat and began.